A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Administration, Building Services, Ford Foundation Headquarters, New Building Planning and Construction Files FA500
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Building Services, Bulk, 1964-1969 1951-1998 (bulk 1964-1969); 1964-1969; V (Box not specified)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- LIN Broadcasting Corp. -- 17th Floor, Apr 3, 1968 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- The Merchandising Group -- 16th Floor, Apr 4, 1968 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- Paul Klemtner & Co., Inc. -- 24th Floor, Sep 12, 1967 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- Phillips, Nizer, Benjamin, Krim & Ballon -- 11th and 12th Floors, May 10, 1968 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- Toshiba America, Inc., Oct 31, 1967-Apr 3, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Sub-Lease -- 477 Madison Avenue -- Vernitron Corp., Oct 10, 1967-Apr 3, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Suggested Stationary -- Samples, Sep 15, 1967 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Supervisory System -- Security Alarms -- Agreement, Nov 12, 1965-Nov 18, 1966 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Taxes and Tax Exemptions -- Correspondence, Notes, Forms and Background Re: Tax Exemptions, Sep 13, 1951-Mar 13, 1967 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Title Insurance, Oct 1965-May 1966 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Tours -- Memoranda and Notes Re: Planning, Aug 22, 1965-Jul 18, 1966 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Tours -- Memoranda and Group Lists, 1966-1968 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - UNIVAC -- Agreement, Memoranda, Purchase Orders, Data, 1955-1965 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Violations -- Correspondence Re: Occupancy, Aug 10, 1967-Apr 29, 1968 (Box 50, Folder 13)
- Images, Bulk, 1963-1968 1963-1999 (bulk 1963-1968); 1963-1968; VI (Box not specified)
  Series VI. Images, 1965-1988 (bulk 1965-1968)
  This series contains visual documentation (slides, photographs, negatives and contact sheets) of the construction and completion of the Ford Foundation Headquarters Building, and its 20th Anniversary in 1987. The majority of the slides depict construction, including site preparation, pouring of the concrete foundation, welding and riveting, fireproofing and electrical work. Additional slides from the same period show the granite quarry in New England that supplied stone for the building, while others portray models of office furnishings. There also are photographs of the building once it was fully staffed and the atrium garden planted (c.1968). Other photographs show the building atrium in December 1970 and the atrium and building exterior in September 1988. In addition, there are a number of contact sheets with images of the various stages of construction and architect Kevin Roche. The photographers were Eugene Cook and Bruce Davidson. Additional photographs, some used in Life magazine, have been separated and retained in frames.
  - Contact Sheets -- Auditorium -- Eugene Cook, [1966] (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Contact Sheets -- Auditorium, etc. -- Eugene Cook, [1966] (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Eugene Cook (1 of 3), [1966] (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Eugene Cook (2 of 3), [1966] (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Eugene Cook (3 of 3), [1966] (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Various -- Eugene Cook (1 of 3), Dec 1-7, 1965 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Various -- Eugene Cook (2 of 3), [1965-1966] (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Various -- Eugene Cook (3 of 3), Jan 25-30, 1966 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Duplicates -- Eugene Cook, [1966] (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Bruce Davidson (1 of 4), 1968 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Bruce Davidson (2 of 4), 1968 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Bruce Davidson (3 of 4), 1968 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Bruce Davidson (4 of 4), 1968 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Designers, Atrium Completion -- Bruce Davidson/Magnum Films, 1966 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Contact Sheets -- Construction -- Kevin Roche -- Bruce Davidson, 1968 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Contact Sheets -- Full View of Site -- Eugene Cook, [1966] (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Contact Sheets -- Full View of Site -- Eugene Cook, Apr 22-30,, 1966 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Contact Sheets -- Laying Pipe -- Eugene Cook, [1966] (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Contact Sheets -- Kevin Roche -- Eugene Cook, [1966] (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Contact Sheets -- Stairs and Stairwell -- 3rd Floor -- Eugene Cook, [1966-1967] (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Contact Sheets -- Unidentified -- Move In?, [1967] (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Contact Sheets -- Widest Views of Building -- Eugene Cook, Jan 18-19, 1966 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Negatives -- 320 East 43rd St. -- 1-109 -- Site Preparation and Hospital Demolition, Aug 26, 1963-May 16, 1964 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Negatives -- 320 East 43rd St. -- 110-242 -- Demolition and Foundation Work, May 19, 1964-Apr 29, 1965 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Negatives -- 320 East 43rd St. -- 243-383, May 6-Dec 23, 1965 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Negatives -- 320 East 43rd St. -- 384-551, Dec 30, 1965-Nov 17, 1966 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Negatives -- 320 East 43rd St. -- 552-694, Dec 1, 1966-Oct 26, 1967 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Negatives -- Color -- Bridge View, [1966] (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Negatives -- Color -- Building Inspectors Looking Through Fence, etc., n.d. (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Negatives -- Color -- Closeup Views of Site, View From Bridge, [1966] (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Negatives -- Color -- North Side 43rd Street, Full View, Floor -- Eugene Cook, [1966] (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Negatives -- Ford Foundation Headquarters -- "Deliver To Mr. Kemp" -- Eugene Cook, [1966] (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Negatives -- Ford Foundation Headquarters -- Trustees Dining Room in Construction, Jun 23 or Sep 27, unknown year (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Negatives -- Ford Foundation Headquarters -- Various, Sep 27, unknown year (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Negatives -- New Building -- William Simmons -- Ford Foundation 431 Rolls A & B 35 mm -- Building Model 4x5 Negatives, May 1965 (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Building Extension Final Installation Work -- A-F, 691-694, Mar 9-Oct 26, 1967 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Foundation Preparation -- 147-169, Jul 8-Dec 31, 1964 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Foundation Construction -- 171-323, Jan 7-Sep 16, 1965 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Site Demolition -- 1-17, Aug 26-Sep 19, 1963 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Site Demolition -- 18-37, Oct 29-Nov 26, 1963 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Site Demolition -- 39-58, Dec 6-21, 1963 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Site Demolition -- 73-84, Dec 31, 1963-May 11, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Site Demolition -- 88-109, May 16, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Site Demolition -- 110-125, May 19-Jun 8, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Photos -- 320 East 43rd St. -- Site Demolition -- 127-146, Jun 15-27, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Photos -- Board Room Entrance -- Esto, [1968] (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Photos -- Building -- Magnum -- Bruce Davidson, 1966 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Photos -- Building Construction -- Black and White -- Eugene Cook, [1966] (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Photos -- Building Construction -- Black and White -- Eugene Cook -- Unidentified Building, [1966] (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Photos -- Building Construction -- Color, [1966] (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Photos -- Building Construction -- Color -- Posterboard Backed, Jun 20, 1966 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Photos -- Building Construction -- Completion -- Artwork -- Garden -- Posterboard Backed -- UPI, [1968] (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Photos -- Building Exterior from 42nd St. -- With Negatives -- Ezra Stoller, [1967] (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Photos -- Carpenters, [1965] (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Photos -- Cementing -- First Slab -- Eugene Cook, Sep 1965 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Photos -- Cementing -- Slab -- Eugene Cook, Oct 25, 1965 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Photos -- Cementing and Foundation (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Photos -- Cementing Slab, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Photos -- Column-Steel Reforms for Column -- Eugene Cook, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Photos -- Dining Room -- Esto, [1968] (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Photos -- Electricians Working on Slab, [1965] (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Photos -- Ezra Stoller Associates -- Building (see also: Slides), [1968] (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Photos -- Finishing Slab -- Leveling Concrete, [1965] (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Photos -- Ford Foundation Headquarters Exterior -- Glassboro State College Art Project -- With Negatives, 1977 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Photos -- Form Work for Wall and Slab, [1965] (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Photos -- Form Work -- Mainly on Walls, [1965] (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Photos -- Forms for Retaining Wall, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Photos -- Foundation Work -- Looking South and Southeast, [1965] (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Photos -- Foundation Work -- Looking West, [1965] (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Photos -- Foundation Work -- Looking West -- Color Transparency and Black and White Photographs, Nov 1965 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Photos -- Garage Slab, Sep 15-16, 1965 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Photos -- Garden -- Bruce Davidson, [1968] (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Photos -- Garden -- Negatives Included -- Ezra Stoller, 1967 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - Photos -- Garden -- Posterboard Backed -- David Lawrence, [1968] (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Photos -- Garden and Plantings -- Dan Kiley -- Dedication Party? -- Contact Prints, [1968] (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - Photos -- Garden in Progress -- Bruce Davidson, [1966] (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Photos -- Human Interest (1 of 2), n.d. (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Photos -- Human Interest (2 of 2), n.d. (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Photos -- Human Interest -- Foundation and Structural Work (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Photos -- Human Interest -- Foundation and Support Work (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Photos -- Human Interest -- Foundation Work (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Photos -- John V. Dinan -- 800 Second Avenue (1 of 3), Apr 13, 1964 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Photos -- John V. Dinan -- 330 E. 43rd St. Sidewalk, North Side, E. 43rd St. (2 of 3), Apr 13, 1964 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Photos -- John V. Dinan -- Sidewalks, Curbs, E. 43rd St., 303 and 303 1/2 E. 43rd St., 305-309, 313, 321 E. 43rd St., Retaining Wall, Site (3 of 3), Apr 13, 1964 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Photos -- Looking East or Southeast -- Eugene Cook, [1965] (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Photos -- Looking East or Southeast -- Black and White pPhotographs, Color Transparencies -- Eugene Cook, Oct 28, 1965 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Photos -- Looking North -- Includes Color Transparencies -- Eugene Cook, [1965] (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Photos -- Looking South -- Color Transparencies -- Eugene Cook, [1965] (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Photos -- Looking South -- Contact Sheets and Color Transparencies -- Eugene Cook, Oct - Nov 1965 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Photos -- Main Conference Room/Auditorium -- Esto, [1968] (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Photos -- Model of New Building -- Ezra Stoller (1 of 2), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Photos -- Model of New Building -- Ezra Stoller (2 of 2), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Photos -- Model of New Building from 42nd and 43rd Streets -- Eric Pollitzer (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Photos -- Neighboring Structures -- Water Seepage from 800 Second Avenue (A-F) -- Mal Gurian, Mar 9, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Photos -- New Building -- Ezra Stoller and Malcolm Smith, [1962-1967] (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Photos -- New Building Model -- Posterboard Backed, [1966] (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Photos -- New York Times Article, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Photos -- Office of the Secretary -- Building of the Ford Foundation -- Building Committee -- Building Public Relations Photographs, [1968] (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Photos -- Parks Department Application -- Pictures of Wall to be Demolished -- Mal Gurian/Ed Whitey, Jul 24-Dec 6, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - Photos -- Pouring Concrete -- Eugene Cook, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 15)
  - Photos -- President's Office -- Esto, [1967] (Box 58, Folder 16)
  - Photos -- Reception Area -- Esto, [1968] (Box 58, Folder 17)
  - Photos -- Reinforcement -- Placing Beam in Site, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 18)
  - Photos -- Reinforcing for Column, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 19)
  - Photos -- Reinforcing for Slab, [1965] (Box 58, Folder 20)
  - Photos -- Reports -- Re-examination -- 328-334 East 34th Street -- Hermitage, Sep 20, 1965 (Box 58, Folder 21)
  - Photos -- Reports -- Re-examination -- 800 Second Avenue, Sep 20, 1965 (Box 58, Folder 22)
  - Photos -- Reports -- Re-examination -- East 43rd Street Areas, Oct 20, 1965 (Box 58, Folder 23)
  - Photos -- Restaurant -- Cafeteria, 1969 (Box 58, Folder 24)
  - Photos -- Retaining Wall, [1965] (Box 58, Folder 25)
  - Photos -- Roche, Kevin -- Plans and Model -- Eugene Cook, Sep 1965 (Box 58, Folder 26)
  - Photos -- Setting Up Beam Site, [1965] (Box 58, Folder 27)
  - Photos -- Tudor City Sixth Unit -- Hermitage from Ford Foundation Lot (#100) Looking East 2pm -- Mal Gurian, May 16, 1964 (Box 58, Folder 28)
  - Prints -- Area Maps, [1971] (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Prints -- Building Sketch and Brochure Cover Art -- Posterboard Backed, [1971] (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Prints -- Ina Taylor's Gift (flipped), Feb 25, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Prints -- UDC Feasibility Study Projections and Blueprints -- Blueprints -- Edward Barnes, Aug 22, 1973 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Prints -- UDC Feasibility Study Projections and Blueprints -- Posterboard -- Edward Barnes (1 of 2), Aug 22, 1973 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Prints -- UDC Feasibility Study Projections and Blueprints -- Posterboard -- Edward Barnes (2 of 2), Aug 22, 1973 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Slides -- Atrium and Exterior, Sep 1988 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Slides -- Building Miscellaneous -- Atrium and 10th Floor, [Dec 1970] (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Slides -- Construction -- Eugene Cook, Nov 1965-Apr 1966 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Slides -- Construction -- Cement Work, Furnishings (Secretarial), etc. -- Eugene Cook, Oct 1965 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Slides -- Construction -- Overall, Auditorium, Fireproofing, etc., Apr-Jun 1966 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Slides -- Construction and Granite Quarry -- Eugene Cook, Aug 1965 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Slides -- Cor-Ten Weathering Samples at 12th Floor 800 Second Avenue -- Mal Gurian Associates, Photographers -- 4 35mm Color Transparencies, Mar 17, 1966 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Slides -- Miscellaneous Building Slides from Broken Sets in Numerical Order -- Ezra Stoller Associates, Inc. -- Esto, [1968] (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Slides -- Model of New Building -- With Prints, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Slides -- New Building Exterior and Garden -- From Robert Mayer, [1967] (Box 59, Folder 11)